so let's begin with the very first cycle
cycle 1 in this cycle there is nothing
to dispatch and nothing to write of
course so the only thing that we really
need to be concerned is with issuing an
instruction the load will look at the
reservation stations and look at
basically the load/store queue in this
case and see that there is an empty
space there so we can issue so we will
mark that this instruction gets done in
cycle 1 as far as issue is concerned now
we have a busy load/store queue entry
the operation is a load now the load
uses an address it doesn't really use a
value so in this case we will use our r2
which is 100 and add 34 to it and that
address will be computed before we put
it in the load/store queue so let's say
that this value is noted here as 134 so
this is really the address we are not
waiting for anything but this load will
produce a floating-point value and put
it in FX so we need to rename f6 to
point to load one and the load doesn't
dispatch in the same cycle because we
said that we cannot do that so this kind
of concludes the issuing of this load
now let's look at the second cycle in
the second cycle we will try to issue
this load and there is a free unit so we
will do that it's 45 from r3 so it's
gonna be 245 again this is done by the
address unit it's not done by the alias
or anything so this addition gets done
immediately and we are not waiting for
anything because Allah doesn't really
need to wait for any floating-point
registers and then f2 is where we're
gonna put a result so we're going to
mark this as LD - and this is it as far
as the issuing is concerned in this
cycle we will dispatch this load now so
its execution begins in cycle 2 because
everything is ready for it and now we
need to consider ok so it takes two
cycles to do a load does the write-back
happen at the end of the second cycle or
does it happen in the cycle after that
in this case we will assume that the
write-back happens after the execution
is done so the execution of the load
will be done in cycles 2 & 3 and the
write-back will happen in cycle 4
so we will kind of note that basically
we will be able to write in cycle four
here just to kind of remember that